so now let's see what happens when we
try to do multiple predictions
simultaneously
suppose we have the classical five stage
pipeline with a fetch decode a leo
memory and write register stages and
suppose that this is where our branches
are resolved in the third stage suppose
also that we have the following program
a branch that jumps to label a if
registers r1 and r2 are not equal
another branch in the program right
after it that compares r1 and r3 and
jumps to label B if they are not equal
then we have some instruction a B C that
are not branches and then we have label
a where we have instructions x and y and
we have then label b where we have
instruction Z suppose that we are using
a not-taken
predictor and at this branch and also
this branch are taken
assuming that we start execution right
here the question for you is how many
cycles are wasted on mispredictions
until we finally get to execute
instruction why because what should be
happening is that we jump after this
branch here and execute x and y what
really happens is that because of our
not-taken prediction we go on and
actually fetch this branch instead so
again how many cycles are overall wasted
on mis-predictions until we correctly
get to y